we're still slogging through the
我们仍然通过苦读
material on machine level programming
在机器语言材料
which is I talked to you earlier I think
这是 我对你前面谈过，我认为
is in some ways the core of this course
在某些方面这门课程的核心
that much of the rest of material builds
那么多剩下的材料构建
upon and hopefully you've all had a
在，希望你们都过
chance to check out lab - and your bomb
机会来看看实验室-和你的 炸弹
lab and you've gotten started on that
实验室，你已经得到了开始对
and certainly by the time you're
当然你的时间是
finished with the material from today
从今天的材料完成
you will be well on the way to solving
你会很好的 方式解决
all but the last one or two stages of
所有，但最后一个阶段或两阶段
the bomb web so I highly recommend you
炸弹的网络，所以我强烈建议 您
get going on that not put it off to the
让事情，不是把它摘下来的
last minute so and what we're talking
最后一分钟 左右，我们正在谈论
about today is is how procedures proceed
今天的程序是如何进行的
I'm going to use the same terminology
我将使用相同的术语
here
这里
whether it's a function a procedure or
无论它是一个功能的程序或
an object-oriented programming a method
一个面向对象的程序设计的方法
those are all roughly the same thing and
这些都是大致 相同的事情，
what we'll talk about covers them
我们将谈论覆盖上
overall
总体
I'll also mention at the outset that the
我还将提到在一开始的
way this is handled in the procedures
这个方法在程序处理
that we'll be talking about today is a
我们将谈论 今天是
combination of the actual x86 hardware
实际x86硬件的组合
and how it supports it but also in some
以及它如何支持它，而且在一些
ways more importantly a set of
方法更重要的是一组
conventions that were developed that
所 开发的 该公约
basically everyone agreed to and it's
基本上每个人都同意，它是
known as an ABI that's why I want to
被称为ABI 这就是为什么我要
wood stands for application binary
木代表的应用程序二进制
interface so the idea is the document
接口这样的想法是文档
you can get it online it's and it's
你可以得到它在网上是和它的
cited in the book it's the document that
在书中引用它的文档
people put together the initial version
人们放在一起 的初始版本
when the first x86 64 machines were
当第一86 64 机器名
first being developed and specifically
第一正在开发和具体地
for Linux they said ok all Linux
适用于Linux，他们说好了所有的Linux
programs that all compilers all the
程序，所有的编译器 的所有
operating system all the different parts
操作系统的所有不同部分
of a system that need to have some
这需要有一些系统的
common understanding of how to manage
如何管理共识
the resources on the machine will agree
机器上的资源会同意
to adhere to this set of rules and so it
坚持 这套规则，所以它
it goes beyond the actual what the
它超越了实际的东西
hardware does to a set of software
硬件确实给一套软件
standards and it's called application
标准，这就是所谓 的应用
binary interface because it's
二进制接口，因为它是
particularly the interface at the
特别是在该接口
Machine level machine level programming
机器级 机器语言
the machine program level and so that's
本机程序级别等这
what we'll be covering today so people
我们会在今天覆盖这样的人
asked sort of well you know who makes up
问那种好，你 知道是谁弥补
these rules and things and the point was
这些规则 和事物和观点是
there was a working group that did this
还有的是，这样做的一个工作组
and there's a separate ABI for Windows
并有 针对 Windows 单独 ABI
it's similar but not quite the same
这是相似但不相同
there's a separate ABI for OSX for Apple
还有的 OSX 苹果单独ABI
and even FreeBSD a different variant of
甚至FreeBSD下的不同变种
a unix-like operating system has its own
类似Unix的操作系统都有自己的
ABI that they all share a lot in common
ABI，他们都在共同分享了很多
but some of the details differ
但一些细节上有所不同
so if you think about what goes on in a
所以，如果你想想在继续
procedure even in C which is a
程序甚至用C这是一个
relatively unsophisticated language in
在相对简单的语言
many ways there's a lot going on and so
很多方面还有很多事情等
it's worth breaking down those and
这是值得打破那些和
thinking about it one is there's a
思考它一个是有 一个
notion of control so in my example I
控制的概念，所以在我的例子中， 我
show a procedure P calling a procedure Q
显示步骤P调用一个方法Q
and so when when P calls Q then somehow
所以当P调用Q时发生后来不知怎的
the program has to jump down and begin
该方案具有 跳下 ，并开始
executing the the lines of code for Q
执行所述的代码Q上的线
and then when Q hits its exit point it's
然后当Q达到其出口点 是
returned point somehow is to get back to
不知何故退回的一点 是要回
P and not just to any old place in P but
P和不只是任何老地方P中，但
specifically to whatever it came comes
专门不管它来到自带
in P right after the call to Q so
在P 中的通话至Q之后使
somehow we have to record the
不知何故，我们必须 记录
information about where the return
哪里的返回信息
should be to be able to return to the
应该是能够返回到
correct place so that's first of all
正确的地方所以这是首先的
passing control to a function and having
将控制传递给功能 ，并且具有
that function return back to where it
该函数返回回到它
should get back to our second lose data
回过头来看看我们的第二个丢失数据
how do we get operands to it so in this
我们怎样才能操作数也因此，在此
particular case Q is a function that
特定情况下，Q 是一个函数，它
takes a single argument that it calls
需要 它调用一个参数
internally it calls i and up here where
在内部调用和 我 在这里哪里
p is calling it it's passing some value
p被称之为它的传递一定的价值
within p called X so hump somehow that
p称为X内，以某种方式驼背那
data value of X has to be recorded in a
X的数据值必须被记录在一个
form that within Q it will have access
形成内e它可以访问
to that information and similarly when q
该信息 并且类似地当q
wants to return a value back up and then
要返回一个值备份，然后
P will make use of that value there has
P将使用该值的存在
to be some convention of how that data
要怎么该数据的一些约定
gets communicated back and then finally
被传递回，最后
in a function might have some local data
在功能可能有一些本地数据
that requires allocation of some amount
这需要一定量的分配
of space and so where does that space
的空间，那么，这是否空间
get allocated how do we make sure it
获得分配我们如何确保 它
gets allocated properly in particular in
被适当地分配特别是在
C as you know when a function returns
C作为你知道当一个函数返回
any local data that it allocated should
它分配任何本地数据应
get D allocated should be freed
得到ð分配应该被释放
so that we don't sort of start consuming
所以，我们不排序的消耗开始
an unbounded amount of storage so how do
存储的无限量，怎么办
we do that those are all the sort of
我们做这些都是何许
different aspects that a procedure call
不同的方面 ， 一个过程调用
and return have to deal with somehow and
和返回必须以某种方式处理 和
part of the reason for breaking it down
为 打破下来 的部分原因
into those little segments is in x86 64
入这些 小片段是在86 64
one of the clever things they did was to
他们做了巧妙的事情之一是
try and reduce the overhead of procedure
尽量减少 程序的 开销
calls as much as possible
要求尽可能地
because as you know in good programming
因为 当你在良好的编程知道
style you often write these functions
风格你经常写这些功能
that do a fairly small amount of actual
该做的实际量非常小
useful stuff and it's sort of good
有用的东西，这有点好
programming style to do that especially
编程风格做特别
in a more object-oriented programming
在一个更面向对象编程
style and so you don't want the overhead
款式等你不想开销
the extra number of steps taken to
所 采取的 步骤额外的数
invoke a procedure and deal with all
调用过程和处理所有
that it's a SPECT
这是一个 SPECT
to take any more time than it needs to
采取更多的时间比实际需要 的
because it's a fairly critical overhead
因为这是一个相当关键的开销
so one of the things they do in in this
所以他们在这做的事情之一
is they only do whatever is absolutely
是他们唯一做的一切是绝对
needed so for in particular if no local
需要所以特别 是如果没有 本地
storage is needed on this for data then
存储需要对这个数据然后
don't allocate it and therefore don't
不分配它， 因此不
free it if you're not passing any values
释放它，如果你不传递任何值
don't pass them and in general sort of
不通过他们，并 在常规排序
how little can you get away with and
怎么一点你可以脱身，
that makes it a little bit confusing
这使得它有点混乱
from a teaching point of view and that
从视图和示教点
there's no set template that it follows
没有它遵循一套模板
every time it's sort of you have to each
每次有那种你 有时间给每个
case is a special case for how a
情况是怎样 一个特例
particular procedure gets implemented so
特别程序 得到实施这样
we'll go through all these parts and see
我们将通过所有 这些部分，看看
how they happen and you've already seen
他们是如何发生的，你已经看到了
little glimpses of them we'll get the
他们的小一瞥 ，我们会得到
little fragments of code that we've
代码的小片段 ，我们已经
shown already so the first one and sort
已经显示出这样的第一个和排序
of the most critical is how do we pass
最关键的是，我们如何把
control to a function but before we can
控制功能，但我们可以前
even talk about that we have to talk
甚至谈到 ，我们要谈谈
about the stack so and you've heard that
有关堆栈所以，你听说过，
term the stack in various ways the stack
术语各种方式堆栈中的堆栈
is really not a special memory it's just
实在不是一个特殊的内存，它只是
a region of the normal memory remember
正常存储的区域记
to the programmers perspective assembly
给程序员透视 装配
level programmers perspective is memory
级的程序员的观点是存储器
is just a big array of bytes and
是字节的只是一个大阵列
somewhere within that bunch of bytes
内的一堆字节的地方
we're going to call it the stack and the
我们要称之为堆栈和
stack is used by the program to manage
堆栈用于通过程序 来管理
the state associated with the procedures
与程序相关联的状态
that it calls and as they return so it's
它调用 和他们返回所以它的
where it passes all these potential
它把所有这些潜在的
information the the control information
信息的控制信息
data and allocates local data and the
数据并分配本地数据和
reason why it can be managed is a stack
之所以可以管理是一个堆栈
is because of the nature of the whole
是因为整个的性质
idea of procedure calls and returns that
过程调用和返回的想法，
you make a call and you might need some
您 拨打一个电话 ，你可能需要一些
information but when you return from a
信息，但是 当你 从 一个 返回
call all that information can be
调用所有这些 信息可以
discarded and so it makes use of that
丢弃，所以它使用的 是
sort of last in first out allocation
排序后进先出分配
principle mesh is very well with this
原则网是非常好，这
idea of procedure call and return so in
过程调用和返回，以便在理念
x86 stacks actually start with a very
86 栈实际上很启动
high numbered address and when they grow
高编号的地址，当他们长大
when more data are allocated for this
当更多的数据被分配给该
deck it's done by decrementing the stack
甲板它是由递减 栈 完成
pointer so the stack pointer as you know
指针，以便你知道堆栈指针
is just a regular register RSP and its
只是一个普通的寄存器RSP 及其
value is the address of the current top
值是当前 顶部 的地址
of the stack and every time you allocate
堆栈，每次分配时间
more space on the stack it does it by
它通过做它在堆栈上更多的空间
decrementing that pointer now just for a
现在递减该指针只是一个
convention and I'm not sure why this
约定，我不知道为什么这
happens but this is the way we do it is
发生但这是我们做的事情是这样的
we draw stacks upside down so that the
我们得出栈倒挂， 使得
term the top of the stack is actually
称之为顶部的堆栈 实际上 是
shown at the bottom
在底部示出
and just to add to that confusion and
而只是添加到混乱 和
also remember that the addresses go from
还记得地址从去
bottom to top
自下而上
not from top to bottom so when you add
不是从上到下，所以当你添加
to the stack you decrement the stack
堆栈你递减堆栈
pointer neither of those kind of meshes
指针既不那些样 网格 的
with your intuition perhaps but you just
用你的直觉可能是，但你就是
have to get used to it because we're not
已经习惯了 它 ，因为我们 不
going to redraw out all this one so
要重绘了所有这一个，这样
anyways that's just remember that over
反正这只是记住了
and over again it and that's why these
一遍又一遍 它，这就是为什么这些
arrows show that if we were to enumerate
箭头显示 ，如果我们列举
the addresses of these different bytes
这些不同的字节的地址
in the data they'd be increasing in this
在数据他们会在这个越来越大
direction and when we add to the stack
方向 ，当我们添加到堆栈
the stack top is at the bottom of the
堆栈顶部位于的底部
picture and we do it by decrementing the
图片， 我们 通过递减做
stack pointer so in particular others
堆栈指针所以特别他人
saw explicit instructions push and pop
看到明确的指示push和pop
that make use of the stack and it's
使使用栈和它的
often written push cue and pop cue but
常写推送 提示和弹出提示，但
that cue is actually an optional suffix
这提示实际上是一个可选的后缀
on the instruction so the the idea of
在指令做的想法
pushing something onto the stack then is
东西推到 堆栈则是
there is some source operand it could be
有一些源操作数也可能是
from register or for memory or an
从寄存器或 存储器 或
immediate so this is sort of like a move
即时所以这有点像 一招
instruction but the destination of the
但指令的目的地
move will be toward memory and that
此举将是对内存和
address of the memory is determined by
存储器的地址由下式确定
first decrementing the stack pointer and
第一递减 堆栈指针和
then doing a right
然后做一个正确的
and similarly the pop instruction takes
类似地弹出指令需要
reads data from the stack and stores it
从堆栈 并存储读取数据
in the destination which must be a
在目的地必须是一个
register for this particular instruction
寄存器对于该特定指令
I think push must be a register too now
我想推必须是注册过，现在
that I think of it for immediate you
我认为它立即您
can't push from memory to so pop reads
不能从内存推到 如此流行读取
from memory the address that reads from
从内存中 读取自 地址
is given by the current stack pointer it
由当前的堆栈指针给出它
and then it increments the stack pointer
然后递增堆栈指针
by 8 these both work only on 8 byte
8这些 都在 8个字节的 唯一工作
operands I'll get to you in a second and
操作数我会得到你在第二和
then the result of that is stored in a
然后，该结果被存储在一个
register question pop and push or just
注册问题pop 和push或只是
like doing the liquidation like is there
喜欢 做清算 就像是有
a difference between like using the like
像使用等之间的差
the top Oh could you write it as a set
顶哦， 你 能不能 把它写成一组
of instructions yeah you could actually
指令是啊，你居然可以
except for some weird corner cases write
除了一些怪异的极端情况写
it out as a set of separate instructions
它作为一组独立的指令
but it's a common enough thing that it's
但它是一个足够常见的事情， 它的
sort of built in as a as an operation
那种建立 在作为作为 操作
whereas call and return are special they
而调用和返回是特殊的，他们
can't be simulated so one thing to
无法模拟这么一件事
remember too is it's important that in
记住太多 是 很重要的，在
one case you decrement you do the
一个情况下，你递减你做的
arithmetic on the stack pointer before
算术上之前，堆栈指针
you write because when you first start
你写的，因为当你第一次启动
it out the stack pointer is pointing to
其 从堆栈指针所 指向的
whatever was the top element of the
无论是的顶级元素
stack we want to create a new top
堆，我们要创建一个新的顶级
element so we're going to decrement
元素，以便我们将 递减
first and then do the right whereas
第一，然后做而右边
going the other direction you want to
会想 其他方向
read off the current top of stack
读出堆栈的当前顶
element and then you want to increment
元素，然后你要增加
the stack pointer to sort of deallocate
堆栈指针进行排序解除分配的
it and one thing you'll notice here is
它和一两件事在这里你会发现是
when I say deallocate it's not like I
当我说释放它不喜欢我
magically erased this or or something
奇迹般地抹去这或什么的
all I'm doing is just moving a stack
我做的只是移动堆栈
pointer whatever was there at the top of
指针无论是那里的顶部
the stack is still in memory it's just
堆栈还在内存中，它只是
no longer considered part of the stack
堆栈不再被认为是部分
okay so that's the idea of the stack and
好了，这就是堆栈的想法，
the instructions push and pop are are to
指令push和pop是 对
put data on the stack or take it off but
把数据在栈上把它关闭，但
we use the same basic idea for a call
我们使用相同的基本 想法 通话
and return so let's look at some
并返回 所以让我们看看一些
examples and there's a lot of stuff up
例子， 有很多的东西了
here but this is a see function called
在这里 ，但这个被称为见功能
mult store and then this is the output
MULT存储，然后这是输出
slightly cleaned up output from the
从 稍微 清理输出
disassembler of that exact function and
该确切功能的拆装和
similarly this is a function called mult
同样，这是一个函数调用MULT
to and this is it's disassembled version
对 ，这就是 它的拆卸版本
and the reason I'm showing this is
其原因我展示这是
because I want to make use of the
因为我想利用的
addresses that these instructions are at
解决了这些指令在
that you don't see when you write it an
你没有看到，当你把它写 的
assembly code so I'm showing it the
汇编代码，所以我展示它的
disassembled version and the reason all
拆卸版本和所有的理由
this is up here is because you'll see
这是在这里是 因为你会看到
the function multi so I want to show how
功能多，所以我想 展示如何
that works so and there's two
该工程 ，以便有两家
instructions and you've seen these in
你已经在看到这些说明
some form to call a function you just
某种形式的只是调用函数 你
call it where you give a label but keep
调用它，你给一个标签，但保留
in mind that this these two instructions
记住，这两个指令
and the other is when you're ready to
另一种是当你准备好
return you just execute the RET
回到你刚才执行RET
instruction and keep in mind though that
指令并牢记 尽管这
these functions don't do the whole
这些功能不会做全
business of procedure call and return
过程调用和 返回 的业务
they just do the control part of it
他们只是做了它的控制部分
which is we saw is only one of three
这是我们看到的仅仅是三选一
aspects of a procedure also mention
程序方面也不在话下
you'll see especially in sometimes it
你会在有时特别是看到它
will say ret semicolon ret and you can
会说RET分号RET，您可以
pretty much just ignore that and it's a
非常简单，只是忽略了，这是一个
bit obscure why it's even there so it's
略显晦涩为什么它甚至有那么它的
really the same idea
真的是同样的想法
okay so let's to break this down into
好了，所以让我们来打破这种分解 成
its simplest part so let's imagine a
其最简单的一部分，所以，让我们 想象
scenario in which the top of stack is at
场景，其中堆栈的顶部是在
hex address 1 to 0 which is not
十六进制为0地址1，其为未
realistic by the way and the program
顺便说一下，程序现实
counter which is called our IP which is
计数器被称为 我们的IP是
not anything to do with death is is
没有任何与死亡 是
indicating that the current instruction
指示当前指令
is this at 5:44 which is this call
这是在5:44这是该呼叫
instruction and so what would happen
指令等会发生什么
with the call instruction is it would do
call指令 是它会做
two things it would actually three
两件事情它会实际上有三个
things it would decrement the stack
事情会递减堆栈
pointer and so subjecting 8 from 1 to 0
指针等 从1到0进行8
and hex gives you 1 1 8 and it would
和六角给你1 1 8，它会
write the address of the instruction
写指令的地址
following to call onto the top of the
以下调用 到 的顶部
stack and it's important that it does it
栈，它很重要， 它 是
the one following the call is it that
在一个 呼叫 以下 是这
that's instruction I'm going to return
这是指导我要回
used for my return address and I want to
用于我的 返回地址，我想
resume execution in this function at the
在该此功能恢复执行
instruction after the call not to call
指令后调用不要 打电话
itself otherwise you'd have an infinite
本身否则你就得 无限
loop and it also this call instruction
循环，它也是这个调用指令
also embedded in the encoding of the
也嵌入在的编码
instruction is the destination address
指令是目的地地址
of it and which happens to be the
它，这恰好是
starting address of this particular
这个特别的起始地址
function so the program counter will be
功能，使程序计数器会
set to that value and now the the
设置为该 值和现在的
processor starts just executing along
处理器刚开始一起执行
these instructions so it did a
这些指令所以它做了一个
combination of a jump and a push and
跳 和推组合
that's why the question was raised
这就是为什么有人提问
earlier is a push instruction could you
早期是推指令 你 能
assemble that out of existing
组装该淘汰现有的
instructions the answer is yes for push
说明答案是肯定的推
but not for call question back there
但不是呼叫问题回到那里
bump in in like both story would put the
颠簸像故事都 将投入
address of multitude in RIT no no it did
在众多 RIT 的地址不，不它做
that RIT you never explicitly there
那你RIT从未明确存在
aren't instructions that manipulate that
不操纵该指令
directly it's implicitly part of the
直接它的隐含部分，
call instruction the call instruction
调用指令调用指令
will take I don't have the actual
将采取我没有实际
encoding but embedded in this call
编码，但嵌入在此调用
instruction you see that it's five bytes
指令你看，它的五个字节
long I don't show you the bike coding
长我不告诉你 的自行车编码
but embedded in it is the target address
但 嵌在它的目标地址
and so it will take that address and use
所以它会采取该地址，并使用
it for the new value of the program
它对于程序的新价值
counter so the call does both the
计数器，以便调用确实既
pushing of the old the return pointer
旧的返回指针 推
and setting the program counter to the
并设置程序计数器到
new the the new target for it so it does
新的新的 目标 ，以便它确实
both of those things
这两点
question
题
I don't think so would either call or
我不认为 这样 会致电或
return if so it would be really obscure
返回如果是的话这将是非常晦涩
no I don't think so no so call and
不，我不这么认为没有那么打电话
return are the there might be some weird
回报是在可能有一些奇怪的
system instructions that let you do that
系统指令，让你这样做
but not in you'd see in any normal
但不是你在任何正常看
program of a question good question so
问题好 问题 的 方案 ，以便
so okay so that shows you the control
这样好了，所以，显示你的 控制
McCall works and then so now imagine
麦考尔的作品，然后 所以现在 想象
this multitude chugs along and it hits
这大军沿一班班和它击中
its return point and it hits this rep
它的回归点，并达到这个销售代表
instruction by the way again ret Q and
顺便说一句指令再次 RET Q和
rather the same instruction and ret will
而相同的指令和RET则
its purpose is to reverse the effect of
其目的是为了扭转的效果
a call it assumes that the top of the
一个称之为假定的顶部
stack has an address that you want to
堆栈有要一个地址
jump to so it will pop that address off
跳到因此它将关闭弹出该地址
the stack meaning it will increment the
堆栈 这意味着将 递增
stack pointer like I said the value
堆栈指针如我说的值
doesn't really disappear from the memory
并没有真正从记忆中消失
it just is no longer considered part of
它只是不再被认为的一部分
the stack and then it will set the
堆栈，然后它将设置
program counter to what it just popped
程序计数器 是 什么，它只是弹出
off the stack and that will cause the
从堆栈 ，这将导致
program to resume back to where it came
程序恢复回到它原来的地方
from
从
so you see that to the clever idea of
所以你看，要的聪明的想法
pushing the address of the next
推下一个地址
instruction so when the return comes it
指令所以当回报是它
will get it to the point where it should
将它得到的地步， 它应该
resume execution
恢复执行
okay so that's passing control it's
还好，这样的传球控制它
pretty simple all these things by the
很简单， 所有这些事情由
way and is just the nature machine code
方式仅仅是本质机器码
every single part of it is pretty simple
它的每一个部分非常简单
because it's designed to be executed by
因为 它的设计由执行
the original hardware is fairly simple
原有的硬件是相当简单
it's not any more but it's really the
它没有 任何更多 ，但它是真正的
basic ideas are and that we use kind of
基本思路是的，我们使用那种
combinations of instructions to build up
指令组合来建立
all the layers associated with
所有的层具有相关联
operations like procedure call and
像过程调用操作和
return okay so passing data now we've
现在我们要回到好了，所以传递数据
already seen a few small examples of
已经看到的 几个 小例子
passing data we've seen a couple
通过数据我们已经看到一对夫妇
registers that get used when you're
当您能够轻松使用的寄存器
passing arguments to a function and
参数传递给 函数，
we've seen the register RA X getting
我们已经看到了寄存器RA X获得
used to return values from a function
用于从函数返回值
and so those that's the basic idea and
所以那些是基本的思路和
again this is all built into this ABI
再次，这是所有内置到这个ABI
you know defined as a set of conventions
你知道定义为 一组 约定
not particularly part of the hardware so
硬件没有特别一部分，从而
in particular the rule is that the first
特别是，规则是 第一
six arguments get passed within these
六个参数得到内这些传递
particular registers and you just have
特别寄存器你不得不
to memorize the order of them or have a
记住 它们的顺序，或者有
table handy to look at or something like
表方便看或类似的东西
that because there's no particular logic
因为没有 特定的逻辑
to it and the return value is returned
它并返回返回值
in register RA X and by the way this is
寄存器RA X，并用的方式，这是
all four arguments that are either
所有四个参数 是要么
integers or pointers well I think I've
整数或指针好，我想我已经
got a little bit unfolding point those
得到了一点点展开的点
are passed in a separate set of
在一组单独 的 传递
registers so these are just for assumed
寄存器，这样这些都只是 假定
now we just are dealing with integer
现在我们只是在处理 整数
data pointer data and then you ask well
数据指针数据，然后你问好
what happens if you have more than six
如果您有 六个 以上会发生什么
arguments to a function which isn't very
参数的函数，而不是很
common but it happens well the rule on
共同但有它发生以及规则上
that is those get put in memory on the
所得到的那些放置在内存上
stack and I'll show straight what I mean
栈，我会告诉笔直我是什么意思
by that so they're passed to the
通过 这样他们传递给
function and then the function has to
函数， 然后将函数必须
retrieve those values off the stack
检索这些值从堆栈
back in the bad old days of ia-32 by the
早在由坏日子IA-32
way all the arguments got passed on the
这样所有的参数得以通过的
stack but now for the most part you pass
叠 ，而 现在你 通过 大部分
arguments and the registers and the
参数和寄存器和
reason for that is register access is
原因是寄存器访问
way faster than memory access okay so
方式比内存访问速度更快好 了，
here's a kind of a messy bunch of code
这里有一种凌乱的 一堆代码
but just to show you how they show up
但只是为了告诉你他们如何现身
all the time in the function not store
在功能上不存储所有的 时间
as three arguments XY and desk and you
三个参数XY和咨询台 ，您
can just see within this code that it's
可以 将此代码 ，它是 内 只看到
making use of of registers like RDI
利用像 RDI 寄存器
and does it show where and in other
并且它显示出在哪里以及其他
places like mult - as two arguments and
像 MULT 的地方 -因为 两个参数，
you can see how it's making use of our
你可以看到它是如何利用我们的
GI and our si and the code so basically
GI和我们的SI和代码，所以基本上
the code is generated under the
该代码是根据所产生的
assumptions that whatever arguments is
假设，无论是参数
being passed to it will be passed in
被传递给它会被传入
that particular set of registers and the
该特定组寄存器和的
particular orders are listed and the
特别是订单已列出，
code is sort of makes those assumptions
代码排序使得 这些假设
and then similarly
然后同样
when you have a return value from a
当你从一个返回值
function
功能
it's the multi-store does not have a
它是多店没有
return values but of mul - does and the
返回值MUL，但是 -不和
way it does is it deposits the value
它的方式是存款的价值
into our ax and then when the return
到我们的斧头，然后当返回
from our X occurs a tumult store you see
从我们的X发生骚乱商店，你看
that it assumes now that the mult store
它现在假定MULT店
code can assume that register RA X holds
代码可以假设寄存器 RA X装
the value of the return value and it can
返回值的 价值 ，它可以
store it in its destination register and
请将其目标寄存器和
we'll look in a minute why RB X gets
我们来看看在一分钟 为什么RB x被
used here we'll cover that in just a
这里使用我们将介绍一些在 短短 的
little later but that's the point that
过了一会儿 ， 但是 这就是点
as long as everyone sticks to this
只要大家坚持这个
common interface standard then you can
通用接口标准，那么你可以
even use different compilers to compile
即使使用不同的编译器来编译
code and have them be able to cooperate
代码，让他们能够合作
with each other in terms of passing
与顺便而言彼此
argue
争论
it's returning data and that's the
它的返回数据 ，这就是
reason why you want that convention yes
你之所以要该公约是
eight bytes because the well first of
八个字节 ，因为良好的第一
all for call and return
所有调用和返回
it's a 64-bit machine so all addresses
这是一个64位的机器 把所有地址
are 64 bits or 8 bytes but also even the
为64 位或8 个字节，而且即使是
push in the pop instruction only work on
推在弹出指令只能 工作于
8 byte values if you said push L if you
如果 8个字节的值 ，如果你说推 大号
tried to write that an X in 64-bit code
试图 写 在 64位代码 的 X
it would come back with a syntax error
它会回来 ， 有语法错误
if you had in the assembly so oh that
如果您在 装配所以 不得不 说 的哦
and that's different I three to there'd
这就是不同的我三 到那里会
be four byte values here okay so like I
在这里 四个字节值 好了，所以我喜欢
said you've certain seen that implicitly
说你 一定看到 隐
and some of the code you've already been
和一些代码，你已经去过
looking at and it's pretty
看，它是相当
straightforward to get an example that
直截了当地得到一个例子
shows passing arguments you have to have
显示你必须有传递参数
a function with at least seven arguments
至少有七个参数的函数
which is pretty messy to do so I won't
做这是相当混乱，所以我不会
do it but there's examples in the book
这样做，但 有 例子在书中
but now and we'll sort of pick it up
但现在我们会有点把它捡起来
I'll show you also in this later part
我还会告诉你在这个后期
and now the third part of it is again
现在它的第三部分， 又是
what if there's some local data that we
如果有一些地方的数据，我们
need to make use of and so to get that
需要利用等，以获取
idea across I have to illness to another
想法跨越我 生病到另一个
concept which is called the stack frame
的概念，它被称为堆栈帧
and so this is a particularly intense
所以这是一个特别强烈
it's used in memory and as I mentioned
它在内存中的使用，并为我所提到的
earlier one of the features of calling
的通话的功能较早的企业之一
and returning is you can imagine when
和返回是你能 想象当
you have a nested series of calls to a
你有一个嵌套的一系列调用到的
function when a particular function is
功能时，一个特定的功能是
executing it only it only needs to
执行仅它只需要
reference the data within that function
该函数内引用数据
or values that have been passed to it
已传递 给它 或值
some which might be pointers and
其中一些可能是指针和
therefore pointing to other locations in
因此指向在其它位置
memory but the point is sort of the rest
内存但问题是排序其余的
of the functions
功能
in your code however many they are are
在你的代码然而，许多却已是
sort of frozen at that moment really
在那一刻， 那种 冰冻真
there's only one function executing at
只有一个在执行功能
any given time I'm assuming a suit of
任何给定的时间我假设的西装
what you'd call a single-threaded model
你会打电话单线程模型
here and so we can just allocate on the
在这里，所以我们可以只分配上
stack whatever space is required for
无论是需要空间的栈
this particular function and then when
这个特殊的功能， 然后当
we return from that function oh we
我们从该函数返回哦，我们
shouldn't if it's correctly written need
应该不会，如果它的正确写入需要
any of the information associated with
任何与相关联的信息
that function that can just sort of
该 功能可以只是有点
disappear forever and that's why this
永远消失，这就是 为什么这个
idea of a stack you allocate something
堆栈的想法你分配什么
if you make more calls you keep
如果你赚更多的电话你保持
allocating more stuff but as they return
分配更多的东西， 但是，当他们返回
you kind of back out of the stack and
你有种背出栈 和
and free things up so the stack
和免费的东西了，因此堆栈
discipline is is exactly the right match
纪律是完全正确的匹配
as well this whole idea of procedure
过程，以及这个整体思路
calling returns so each block we use for
调用了回报，每次我们使用的块
a particular call then it's called a
特定的呼叫，然后它被称为
stack frame and to be suitum more
栈帧和要suitum 更
technical we'll say it's a frame for a
技术我们会说这是对的一框
particular instance of a procedure a
的过程的特定实例
particular call to a procedure so just
对一个过程特定呼叫所以才
imagine we had a set of functions one
想象我们有一组 功能中的一个
called you which calls a function called
叫你这就要求调用函数
who and who has multiple calls to
谁和谁拥有多个呼叫
another function called MI and mi is
所谓的MI和MI的另一个功能是
itself recurrence recursive it calls
本身复发递归调用
itself and so an imagine we had a chain
本身这样的想象，我们有一个链
of calls where you call two calls
在那里你拨打两个电话通话
mi which calls itself recursively twice
MI 自称递归两次
and then we'll exit out of MI and get
然后我们将退出MI出来，并得到
back to who and then who will hit it
回到谁和谁就会 打
second call to mi which won't go any
第二次调用英里， 不会去任何
further and that will be it so this
进一步，这将是它所以这
picture here shows the soul whole
此 图为整个灵魂
history of all these calls that get made
所有这些调用，获得由历史
but in terms of the stack of
但在堆的条款
all we need what will keep a frame for
所有我们需要的 将保持框架
every sort of procedure that has been
各样程序已
called but not yet returned on this deck
所谓但这甲板上还没有恢复
and in general this deck of is delimited
和一般这种甲板的被分隔的
by delimited by two pointers one is the
由两个指针界定一个是
stack pointer which we're familiar with
堆栈指针这是我们所熟悉的
and then there's another called the base
再有另一个 称为 基
pointer which register RB P indicates
指针哪个寄存器RB P表示
but one a feature of actually it's now
但 一个实际功能是现在
become a feature of ia32 as well is that
成为IA32的特点，以及 是
this is an optional pointer and in
这是一个可选的指针和在
particularly the code that we'll see
特别是我们将看到的代码
does not use a base pointer except in
不使用基址指针除了在
some very special cases so this this
一些非常特殊的情况下， 所以这本
register doesn't really won't show up in
寄存器并没有真正 将不会出现 在
your programs being used in a special
在一个特殊的使用你的程序
way as a frame pointer it will be used
的方式作为一个帧指针将使用它
instead just as a regular register so
而不是仅仅作为一个经常性寄存器，
typically then the only thing you'll
通常那么你唯一会
know about the stack pointer you
知道堆栈指针你
wouldn't even be able to figure out
甚至不能够 搞清楚
where where the frame is exactly you'll
其中框架正是在那里你会
just know that the top part of the stack
只知道堆栈的顶部
is the top frame for the topmost
是 用于 最上面 的 顶部 框架
function and this is all managed by the
功能，这 是所有被管理
code itself and this is the same stack
代码本身，这是相同的堆栈
by the way in which you're pushing and
顺便说一下在你推和
popping addresses - and they all kind of
弹出地址 -他们都挺
get mixed together
得到混合在一起
so we haven't actually seen any code up
所以我们还没有真正看到 任何代码了
til now that makes you have to do any
直到现在，让你做 任何
explicit management of the stack because
堆栈因为明确的管理
all our examples were very simple and
我们所有的例子 都非常简单，
just did a made use of the stack only
只是做了一个利用堆栈的唯一
for return addresses but we'll see some
对于返回地址 ， 但 我们会看到一些
that uses more but so in general then
在一般的使用更多，但这样的话
imagine that each time you begin a
可以想象，每次 开始
function some space key delicated
功能精巧的一些空格键
potentially on the stack for its frame
潜在地在堆叠其帧
and then and that frame is indicated by
然后和帧由指示
either one pointer only or two pointers
任一个指针只或两个指针
and so now as you calls who then that
所以现在，你叫谁那么
will create a new stack frame for who
将创建 谁 一个新的堆栈帧
and some way when mi gets called that
当MI被调用的一些方法
creates the new stack frame and as we
创建新的堆栈帧和我们
continue with these recursive calls
继续与 这些递归调用
we're just adding more stuff to the
我们只是增加了更多的东西给
stack getting deeper and deeper and that
堆越来越深 ，并且
will keep happening it's one of the
将继续发生它的一个
reasons why recursion is a little bit of
原因是递归一点点
a risky thing is that it compared to
冒险的一件事是，它比
iteration it keeps requiring more space
迭代它不断要求更多的空间
as you go deeper in the recursion and in
如您在递归和走向深入
particular most systems limit the total
特别是大多数系统限制总
depth of the stack and you can have what
堆栈的深度，你能有什么
because they're they're afraid of the
因为他们是他们害怕 的
sort of infinite loop version of
排序的无限循环 版本
recursion is runaway recursion where it
递归失控递归的地方
just keeps trying to push more and more
只是不断努力推动更多
stuff onto the stack that's an aside and
东西到堆栈 这是一个一边 ，
then as these begin to return they those
然后这些开始返回他们的
frames get de-allocated removed from the
帧需要解除分配从取出
stack so part of it it the nice thing
所以堆栈的一部分它 的好处
about this is it means that every time I
关于这是不是就意味着我 每次
if I have multiple calls to MI because
如果我有多个呼叫MI因为
I've gone deep recursively each one of
我已经深深的递归的每一个
them will have its own local state that
他们将有自己的本地状态
it needs to manage and again the whole
它需要管理和再整
stack discipline is what makes it work
堆栈规则是 什么使得它的工作
and what we'll find out in particular is
而我们会发现 ，特别是
because of the way this is set up
因为 这种 方式 设置
recursive calls are handled the same way
递归调用 相同的方式处理
that
那
regular calls are there's nothing
普通电话是没有什么
special about them all the heart all the
特别之处他们所有的心脏一切
sort of infrastructure required to
排序的基础设施要求
support recursion is built into this
支持递归内置到该
whole stack discipline
整个堆栈纪律
so anyways imagine that all these calls
所以反正想象所有这些电话
return back to who and then who would
返回到谁，那谁愿意
call mi again and then again as we exit
再 一次 ，然后 调用 宓 为我们退出
we were sort of deallocating these stack
我们有点重新分配这些堆栈
frames and getting back to the starting
帧，又回到了起点
point
点
yes question oh so the question was if
是的问题是如此的问题是，如果
RB P is optional
RB P是可选
then how does the program know how to do
然后程序如何 知道该怎么办
the D allocation how can it reset the
对D分配如何才能重置
stack back to the right place and the
堆栈恢复正确的地方和
answer is and we'll see examples that
答案是，我们将看到的例子是
the code is compiled so it knows for
在编译代码，以便它知道了
example when it does the allocation is
当 它 例子 的分配是
going to allocate 16 bytes and then it
要分配16个字节，然后将 它
knows at the end that it can be
知道在最后，它可以是
allocated 16 bytes and it actually
分配的 16个字节，它 实际上
brings up a good point there is sort of
带来了一个好点的有几分
an obscure part of the book that goes
这本书的一个不起眼的一部分去
over this there's a few special cases
在这个有一些特殊情况
where it can't know in advance how much
它不能提前知道 多少
space will be allocated when it has to
当有空间将被分配
allocate an array or a memory buffer of
分配的阵列或存储器缓冲器
variable size and then it will actually
变量的大小，然后它实际上将
use the the RB P in those cases for
使用的RB p在这些情况下， 为
exactly that purpose
正是目的
okay and so in general that what the
还好 ，因此普遍 认为是什么
stack frame will look like in one of
栈帧将看起来像在之一
these machines will be something like
这些 机器将会像
this that look and you'll see this is
这 看起来，你会看到 这是
the caller and then this is the the
来电者，然后这是的
stack frame of the the function that got
的，进行了该函数的堆栈帧
called so working our way back if we
调用，所以工作回来的路上，如果 我们
have to pass more than six arguments the
必须通过六年多的争论
caller will actually use its own stack
主叫方会真正使用它自己的堆栈
frame to store those arguments and so
帧存储这些参数等
that they'd be available and we already
他们会是可用的，而且我们已经
saw when you do a call it will push the
看到当你调用它会推动
return address onto the stack so before
返回地址 压入堆栈如此前
a function even starts all this
功能甚至开始 这一切
information would be on the stack now if
信息会 在堆栈上，如果现在
there's a if this particular if we're
有一个，如果这个特殊的，如果我们
making use of a base pointer then we
利用 基类指针 的 那么我们
have to have some way where to store the
必须有某种方式在哪里存储
old value of the base pointer so that we
基指针的旧值， 使我们
could fix it back when we return we
可以修复它回来时，我们回到 我们
won't show any code doing that here so
不会显示任何代码，这样做，所以在这里
this is optional but in general if
这是可选的，但 一般来说，如果
there's some local state like some
有一些地方的国家像一些
registers that need to be saved can
需要保存的寄存器可以
we'll see examples of that or an array
我们将看到 一个或一个数组 的例子
that needs to be allocated locally that
这需要在本地所分配
will be stored within the stack frame
将被存储在堆栈帧中
and there might be some requirement for
并有可能对某些要求
some extra space in the stack frame for
在栈帧的一些额外的空间
other stuff in particular if it we're
特别是其他的东西，如果我们
going to pass more than seven arguments
要通过七年多的参数
that need space somewhere in the stack
这一需求空间，在堆栈的某处
frame to do it
框架做
and what we'll see in typical a code is
而我们将在典型的看到一码
this stack pointer gets decremented
这个堆栈指针被递减
pretty soon after the procedure begins
不一会儿程序开始后，
and it gets incremented back just before
它被加回之前
it returns
它返回
that's how it manages this deck so let's
这是怎么管理这个平台 让我们
do some examples
做一些例子
um what he looked at this before but
嗯 什么，他看着这之前，但
this is a function oh I think the
这 是一个功能哦，我想
interesting thing about this function is
关于这个功能有趣的 是 ，
that it has a pointer being passed to it
它有一个指针被传递给它
so this function takes an argument one
所以这个功能需要一个 参数一个
argument is a pointer or another is a
参数 是一个指针或另一种是
integer value and you can see what it
整数值，你可以看到它
does is that dereferences that pointer
确实是取消引用该指针
to get a value code X it computes a
得到一个值码 X是一个计算
value Y by summing X and the value
通过总结X和 值值Y
passed to it it stores Y back at P but
传递给它，它存储Y内为P，但
it returns X the original value of the
它返回X 的原始值
pointer not the updated version of the
指针没有更新的版本
pointer and you can see that in the code
指针，你可以看到，在代码
here it's code pretty short remember
在这里它的代码很短 记得
that in general Rd I will hold the first
在一般的 路我将举行 第一次
argument in this case it's a pointer so
在这种情况下，争论它是一个指针 ，以便
it will do a read from that pointer and
它将从指针做一个读和
it will put the value in our ax which is
它会把这是 我们 的斧头价值
where the return value should be anyhow
在返回值应该是无论如何
and then it will increment our si which
然后它会增加我们的SI其
has the value called Val here initially
有一个叫瓦尔这里最初的价值
and now it has the value of x plus Val
现在它有 X加瓦尔的 价值
and then it will store that in the value
然后将其存储 在值
pointed to by P and it will do a return
指向P和它会做一回
so you see these three instructions do
所以 你看 ， 这三个指令做
all the different parts of this and as
这一点，并为所有不同的部分
this shows in general also you know
这说明一般也知道
register usage it's handy by the way to
顺便说来注册使用它的方便
document this when you're looking at
这个文件时，你在 看
code rgi is the first argument RSI gets
代码RGI是第一个参数 RSI变
used initially it's Val but now it will
最初使用它的瓦尔但现在它会
be set to Y during the call and
在通话过程中被设定为Y和
similarly our ax is initially the value
同样我们的斧最初 值
well it's it's both what X is here and
那么这是 它的两个 是在这里 什么X 和
it's used as a return value
它被用来作为返回值
okay so what's the reason to go through
好了，什么是 要经过 的 原因
all that is to actually show you
所有这些都是真正告诉你
examples of calling this and how
调用这个实例，以及如何
arguments get passed to the function and
参数得到传递给函数和
how it makes use of the stack
它是如何利用堆栈
so now there's a function called call
所以现在有一个函数调用调用
incre and it's going to create a value
增量值和它要 创建一个值
called vet v1 and have to generate a
所谓的兽医 v1和具有生成
pointer to that so what that means is v1
指针， 所以这是什么意思为v1
can't just stay in a register because
不能仅仅停留在一个寄存器 ，因为
you can't create an address of a
您不能创建的地址
register it has to be stored in memory
注册它必须被存储在存储器
somewhere so that you can create a
这样的地方， 你 可以创建一个
pointer an address of it and where does
指针是一个地址，在哪里呢
it store it what puts it in the stack so
其存储 该怎么把它在栈中，以便
how does it find space on the stack will
它是如何找到堆栈空间将
allocate so the function call inker then
这样分配的函数调用着墨然后
and we'll go through all the different
我们会经历 各种 不同的
parts of it but you see that this red
它的 一部分 ，但你看到这个红色
code here is generated generates these
这里生成的代码生成这些
two instructions
两个指令